# Mahammadayan S. Shaikh

## Software Engineer

(e)

+91 6355156937

ayanshaikh18



mahammadayan18@gmail.com



Mahammadayan Shaikh

#### **About Me**

A software engineer with 1 year of experience in the development of applications using Java, Spring Boot, React JS, and PostgreSQL. A focused individual with a good understanding of technologies and an aim of delivering quality business applications and products. A team player with good communication and interpersonal skills.

## **Career Vision**

Seeking a position in the software development industry to utilize my skills and abilities, which can help me grow in this field. I aim to use my expertise and learning to build quality products that can have a positive impact on the citizens of the country and ultimately contribute to the country's prosperity in this ever-growing field of opportunities.

# **Professional Work Experience**

# Ignosi Systems Pvt. Ltd. (Ignosis) - Software Engineer (June 2022 - Cont.)

Tools &Technologies - Java, Spring Boot, React JS, AWS, PostgreSQL, Jasper, JPA, Query DSL, Liquibase, Docker, Git, Swagger

Key Responsibilities -

- Working as a Full Stack Developer.
- Worked on RBI powered Account Aggregator Project which enables the Digital Data Sharing for enhancing & expanding Loan Underwriting, Loan Monitoring, Personal Finance Management, Loan Collection and many more fintech use cases.
- Have been involved in the designing, implementing & maintaining project from scratch.
- Designed and implemented backend APIs using Spring Boot framework. Used concepts and technologies like Spring Security for authentication, Spring Data JPA for DB communication, Dynamic PDF generation using jasper, dynamic excel generation using Apache POI, used AWS SDK toolkit for using SES & S3 of AWS in spring boot.
- Followed Best practices of Software Development Life cycle consisting requirements gathering, designing & development, Git branch management, Code review, UAT Testing etc.
- Managed basic deployments on AWS cloud.
- Implemented multi-tenant architecture in the project.

# Pirimid Fintech - Software Engineer Intern (August 2021 - May 2022)

Tools & Technologies - Java, Spring Boot, React JS, PostgreSQL, Jasper, JPA, Query DSL, Docker, Git

Key Responsibilities -

- Learnt & understood about various tools & technologies required for the software development like git, java, Spring Boot, Javascript, React JS.
- Designed, implemented & tested easily integrable Backend REST APIs for the Account Aggregator project and made those APIs production ready.

# Root Force Marketing - Web Development Intern (May 2021 - July 2021)

Tools & Technologies - Django, Javascript, JQuery, Html, Git

Key Responsibilities -

- Designed database and developed backend for email automation functionality.
- Automated mailing for user with the help of Send grid API.
- Automated SMS and Web Push Notifications.

## **Projects**

## Online Assessment System | December 2020

Tools & Technologies - Django, Javascript, JQuery, Html, Git, SQLIte Database

- Online web application that provides a single platform for university CS faculties and students to automate the practical evaluation & management of coding subjects.
- The application manages the assignments using classroom like functionality where coding laboratory assignments can be easily assigned, tracked & tested using test cases evaluation.
- It provides features like code compilation, running & testing code on test cases, automatic grade generation, coding contest hosting etc.

Source Code - <a href="https://github.com/ayanshaikh18/SDP\_Online\_Assessment\_System">https://github.com/ayanshaikh18/SDP\_Online\_Assessment\_System</a>

#### Instagram Clone | June 2021

Tools & Technologies - ReactJs, Node JS, Express JS, Mongodb, CSS

- Instagram clone developed using MERN stack for understanding and learning the tech stack.
- UI is designed using react-styled-components.

Source Code - <a href="https://github.com/ayanshaikh18/insta-clone">https://github.com/ayanshaikh18/insta-clone</a>

#### Beatbuzzz - Online Music Player | Sept. 2020

Tools & Technologies - Angular JS, Node JS, Express JS, Mongodb

- An online music player application developed using MEAN stack to provide free songs & music to users.
- Users can listen to songs added by Admin. They can view playlists created by Admin and can also create their own playlists as well.

Source Code - https://github.com/ayanshaikh18/Online-Music-Player

## **Education**

## **Bachelor of Technology in Computer Engineering**

Dharmsinh Desai University, Nadiad, Gujarat (July 2018 - May 2022) CPI - 9.31

#### **Higer Secondary | Class XII**

Sett R.J.J. High School, Valsad, Gujarat (June 2016 - June 2018) Percentage - 89.60 Percentile - 99.70

#### Secondary | Class X

Sett R.J.J. High School, Valsad, Gujarat (June 2015 - June 2016) Percentage - 94.67 Percentile - 99.97

## **Personal Details**

Full Name - Mahammadayan Shabbirahmed Shaikh DoB - 14/08/2000 Gender - Male Marital Status - Single Languages - English, Gujarati, Hindi